# Gabriele Marini

Italian, 12th of September 1992
giaga7@gmail.com
marinig@student.unimelb.edu.au
(+61) 481149376

Melbourne, Australia LinkedIn: @gabryxx7 Github: @gabryxx7

### Summary

Third year PhD Candidate at the University of Melbourne, sponsored by CSIRO-Data61. My research focuses on indoor localisation, sensors and modeling. I am very passionate about research and especially ubiquitous computing but I often work with 3D graphics (Unity mostly) and Android.

#### Education

# PhD in Computing and Information Systems

May 2018 - Ongoing

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, Australia

Third year PhD Candidate. Expected graduation: May 2021

#### PhD in Computing and Information Systems

May 2018 - Ongoing

CSIRO - Data61. Melbourne, Australia

# MSc in Computer Science (Laurea Magistrale)

Jun 2017

*Universitá degli Studi di Pisa.* Pisa, Italy Final grade: 110/110 *cum laude* 

#### **BSc in Computer Science**

Jul 2014

Universitá degli Studi di Cagliari (Laurea Triennale). Cagliari, Italy

Final grade: 110/110 cum laude

## Experience

#### PhD Candidate

Jul 2018 - Ongoing

University of Melbourne. Melbourne, Australia

- Member of the NHMRC Center for Research Excellence
- Treasurer of the CIS Research Students Association (CIS-GReS)
- **Teaching**: Tutoring includes material creation, teaching and exams/projects marking.
- INFO90003 (2020): Designing Novel Interaction
- COMP30019 (2018, 2019 and 2020): Computer Graphics and Interaction
- SWEN20003 (2019): Object Oriented Software Development
- Equipment manager for the IDL lab
- Floor Warden

Consultant

Oct 2017 - Feb 2018

European Central Bank (ECB). Frankfurt, Germany

I worked on the long-term IReF project. I implemented an online survey to be sent out to all the banks in Europe. Besides that, I offered technical support for IT-related matters (Python scripts, WordPress websites management, Javascript, VBA)

#### Research Assistant

Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

TeCIP Institute, Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna. Pisa, Italy

I worked mostly on robot vision and Hand-Eye camera robot calibration. I also developed part of the HMI (C#, MySQL) with a 3D Viewer of the robotic arm with inverse kinematics

**Intern** Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

VRMedia - Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna. Pisa, Italy

I developed and wrote my master thesis under the supervision of Prof. Franco Tecchia.

# Technical skills

**Programming Languages:** C++, C#, C, PHP, Java, Python

Data Analysis/Visualisation: R, Python, Javascript (and NodeJS), SQL, MySQL, Mat-

₋ab

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript (and NodeJS), PHP

Markup Languages: Latex, Markdown, YAML, HTML, XML, JSON

Tools/Framework: Many IDEs and notebooks such as PyCharm, Eclipse, Jupyter, RStu-

dio, Unity3D, Photoshop, Blender, WordPress

# Projects Sema

# Semantic Indoor Localisation, PhD Research Project

Supervisor: Prof. Vassilis Kostakos

#### Emotion Recognition with Affectiva, Side project at UniMelb

Developed as a way of interacting with PCs through emotions and facial expressions, we used the Affectiva SDK and C# on Windows or Java on Android.

## Injection of a scripting language into the Unreal Engine, Master thesis

Supervisor: Prof. Franco Tecchia

# MeshLabJS Texture and .zip support, Final project

Supervisor: Prof. Paolo Cignoni

#### Interactive shoes showcase, Bachelors thesis

Supervisor: Prof. Riccardo Scateni

#### Languages

- Italian, Native speaker
- English, fluent, TOEFL: 112 (C2)
- Spanish, Intermediate
- Portuguese, Beginner

#### Certificates

<ul> <li>MTC-GR - Melbourne Teaching Certificate for Graduate Research</li> </ul>	Nov 2019
• WWCC - Working With Children Certificate	Feb 2019
UniMelb Tutor Development Program	Jun 2018
• RIOT - Research Integrity Online Training	Jun 2018
• TOEFL 112/120 (Reading: 28, Listening: 28, Speaking: 26, Writing: 30)	Sep 2017

#### Awards

- PhD Scholarship awarded by CSIRO Data61
- Top graduates award awarded by Universitá di Pisa
- Top graduates award awarded by ERSU Cagliari

# Relevant courses

- Designing Novel Interaction (Distinguished Project Award)
- Research Methods Computer Graphics Linear Algebra
- Introduction to Robotics Virtual Environments
- Programming Languages and Compilers Advanced Databases
- Advanced Programming Advanced Algorithms

# Additional Activities

- SV (Student Volunteer) at UbiComp 2020 in Cancún, Mexico (postponed to 2021)
- Doctoral Colloquium and Workshop presenter at UbiComp 2019 in London, UK
- SV (Student Volunteer) at UbiComp 2019 in London, UK
- Open Day Volunteer at the University of Melbourne, Australia
- SV (Student Volunteer) and attendee at OzCHI 2018 in Melbourne, Australia
- Attended UbiComp 2018 in Singapore

## Extras

- Amateur photographer (landscape, astro-photography and aerial)
- Traveller and backpacker
- Long distance and open water swimmer

# **Publications**

 Marini. G, Tag B, Goncalves J, Velloso E, Jurdak R, Kostakos V. A System to Quantify Mobility and Occupancy Levels in Clinical Settings: Development and Implementation, DOI: 10.2196/preprints.19874

- 2. <u>G. Marini</u>. Towards indoor localisation analytics for modelling flows of movements. 2019. International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp '19 Adjunct) 377–382. doi:10.1145/3341162.3349306
- 3. <u>G. Marini</u>, J. Gonçalves, E. Velloso, R. Jurdak, and V. Kostakos. 2019. Towards context-free semantic localisation. International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp '19 Adjunct), 584–591. doi: 10.1145/3341162.3349329.
- 4. Northern Health gets its teeth into patient flow. 2019. VicHealth [URL]
- W. Jiang, <u>G. Marini</u>, N. Berkel, Z. Sarsenbayeva, Z. Tan, C. Luo, X. He, T. Dingler, J. Goncalves, Y. Kawahara, V. Kostakos. 2019. Probing Sucrose Contents in Everyday Drinks Using Miniaturized Near-Infrared Spectroscopy Scanners. Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT), 3(4), 136:1–136:25. doi: 10.1145/3369834. [ERA: A\*].
- W. Jiang, G. Marini, N. Berkel, Z. Sarsenbayeva, C. Luo, X. He, T. Dingler, Y. Kawahara, V. Kostakos. 2018. A Mobile Scanner for Probing Liquid Samples in Everyday Settings. 19 International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing Adjunct (UbiComp Adjunct). ACM, 1172–1177. doi: 10.1145/3267305.3274764.
- 7. Z. Sarsenbayeva, G. Marini, N. van Berkel, C. Luo, W. Jiang, K. Yang, G. Wadley, T. Dingler, V. Kostakos, J. Goncalves, "Does Smartphone Use Drive our Emotions or vice versa? A Causal Analysis", in Proceedings of ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'20), 2020, to appear.
- 8. D. Hettiachchi, Z. Sarsenbayeva, F. Allison, N. van Berkel, T. Dingler, <u>G. Marini</u>, V. Kostakos, J. Goncalves, ""Hi! I am the Crowd Tasker" Crowdsourcing through Digital Voice Assistants", in Proceedings of ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'20), 2020, to appear.